#8: Skeleton animation
#8: 骨架动画
Let's get back to the character we've made.
回到我们做好的角色上。
Now we are going to make him walk.
我们要让他走两步。
Let's put the character into initial position, just like this.
先把角色安放到起始位置，像这样。
And then we switch into Animation mode.
现在切换到动画模式中。
We are going to have it take 16 frames to make a step.
我们打算一步用16帧。
Move the time cursor to frame 16 and add a new keyframe.
移动时间光标到16并添加一个新关键帧。
Now we have to switch the legs position and move the whole figure forward.
现在我们要对换腿的位置并把整个任务往前移。
But first I would like to mark the position of his fore leg.
不过我想先标记一下他在前的腿。
For that purpose just create a small circle right here, as a marker.
为此创建一个小圆到这里，作为一个标记。
Now we can switch the legs...
现在我们可以交换双腿了...
...and move the guy forward.
...然后移动他向前。
Like this, so this leg should remain in the same place.
就这样，这条腿应当还在原位。
And don't forget to switch the arms as well.
当然也不要忘了交换手臂。
For now the movement doesn't look that good.
目前动作看着不顺眼。
Obviously the character should raise one leg while walking...
显然的，移动的时候，角色应该抬起一条腿...
...and the other should stay on the ground.
...另一条腿就应该踩在地上。
So we'll create an in-between keyframe and fix the pose.
我们创建中间的过渡关键帧，调整姿势。
Since this leg is the fore one, it stays on the ground.
这是前腿，应该站在地上。
And this one will go up.
而这一天应该抬起来。
I am clicking the bone point to mark it.
我点击骨骼的点来标识它。
You can see it's highlighted now, so I can distinguish it from the other bones.
你能看到它高亮显示了，所以我能从其它骨骼中把它区分出来。
To make our animation even better, We'll put an emphasis on the moment when character shifts his weight to the fore leg.
为了让动画更漂亮，我们在角色转移重心到前腿的那一刻给个强调。
Add a keyframe here...
此处添加一个关键帧...
...and then we adjust the foot to emphasis the step.
...然后我们通过调整足部动作来强调这一步。
Like this.
像这样。
The first step is done.
第一步做好了。
We'll make the second exactly the same way.
我们要用完全相同的方法做第二步。
Mark the position of the fore leg...
标记前腿的位置...
Add the key pose, when a character has already completed the second step.
当角色完成第二步时，添加关节姿势。
This pose is the same as the beginning.
此处姿势和开头一模一样。
So we can just copy the keyframe...
所以只要拷贝一下这个关键帧...
... and move the character to the right position.
... 移动角色到恰当的位置。
Now we'll add an in-between frame again.
现在我们要再次添加一个过渡帧。
This time, this leg is on the ground...
这次，是这条腿站在地上...
...and this one in the air.
...而这条抬起在空中。
Then emphasize the movement at the step.
然后强调一下这一步的移动。
And now we have two steps ready.
我们做好了两步了。
For the third step you can simply copy the keyframes and keep moving the character forward.
对于第三步你可以简单拷贝这些关键帧并保持角色向前移。
But before we do that, let's name the frames to avoid messing up.
不过做之前，我们给这些帧起名以避免混乱。
Let's name them as follows:
起名如下:
"0", "0-step" ...
"0", "0-step" ...
"0-to-1", "1"...
"0-to-1", "1"...
"1-step"...
"1-step"...
"1-to-0"...
"1-to-0"...
...and, again, "0".
...然后, 又是, "0".
Now mark the position of this leg...
现在标记这条腿的位置...
And copy the frames.
拷贝这些帧。
We properly need to go through all the keyframes...
我们需要全部关键帧...
...  and adjust the main bone of the character so its feet don't appear slip against the ground.
...  然后调整角色的主骨骼让他的足部不会在地板上打滑。
OK, it's done.
好，这样就做完了。